Unlock the secret.
Hugo is a adventure, drama, family film directed by Martin Scorsese.
Orphaned and alone except for an uncle, Hugo Cabret lives in
the walls of a train station in 1930s Paris.
Hugo's job is to oil and maintain the station's clocks, but to him, his more important task
is to protect a broken automaton and notebook left to him by his late father.
Accompanied by the goddaughter of an embittered toy merchant, Hugo embarks on a quest to
solve the mystery of the automaton and find a place he can call home.
Hugo Cabret, played by Asa Butterfield.
Georges Méliès, played by Ben Kingsley.
Isabelle, played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Station Inspector, played by Sacha Baron Cohen.
Uncle Claude, played by Ray Winstone.
Lisette, played by Emily Mortimer.
Hugo is a 2011 American adventure drama film directed and produced by
Martin Scorsese, and adapted for the screen by John Logan.
Based on Brian Selznick's 2007 book The Invention of Hugo Cabret, it tells the story of a boy who lives alone in the Gare Montparnasse railway station in
Paris in the 1930s, only to become embroiled in a mystery surrounding his late father's automaton and the pioneering filmmaker Georges Méliès.
Hugo is Scorsese's first film shot in 3D, about which the filmmaker remarked, "I found 3D
to be really interesting, because the actors were more upfront emotionally.
Their slightest move, their slightest intention is picked up much more precisely."
The film was released in the United States on November 23, 2011.
Despite receiving considerable acclaim from critics, Hugo was a financial
disappointment, grossing only $185 million against its estimated $150 million budget.
The film received 11 Academy Award nominations (including Best Picture), more than any other film that year, winning a leading five
awards: Best Cinematography, Best Art Direction, Best Sound Mixing, Best Sound Editing, and Best Visual Effects.
It was also nominated for eight BAFTAs, including Best Director, and winning two, and was
nominated for three Golden Globes, including Scorsese's third win for Best Director.
The film explores themes of paris, france, based on
novel or book, library, clock tower, key.
The tone is emotional.